[Music]
let's take a closer look at Bea's
interactive data tables
you'll see five sections on the left
hand side of the website General
National
industry
International and Regional data
you can hover over each section to see
what each section includes
let's say you're looking for a national
GDP statistics or national consumer
spending figures
or business investment Nationwide then
click on GDP and personal income under
the National Data section
looking for how Industries are doing and
their contributions to the overall
economy
click on GDP by industry under the
industry data section if you're
interested in trade and direct
investment statistics between the United
States and other countries
then select International transactions
for trade and the direct investment
options for direct investment data
if you want to see personal income or
GDP for your state metro area or County
select GDP and personal income under the
regional data section
those are just a few examples of what we
have to offer
for a quick tour let's explore GDP
statistics on a national level
specifically let's look up the United
States economy's growth rate in a given
quarter select GDP and personal income
under the National Data section and then
select interactive data tables
you'll see there are a lot of options to
choose from
you want Section 1 domestic product and
income now click on table 111 for
percent change in real or
inflation-adjusted GDP you can see
growth rates or declines for GDP by
quarter if you want data for different
quarters or even years click on the
modify icon
quarterly data goes back to 1947 and
annual data goes back to 1929. here's
how you can pull data for different time
periods using the modify button
let's do years
you can select the box next to first
year and select the earliest year of
your choice
next click the button next to last year
and select the most recent year of your
choice you can also gather your
information by quarters or annual in the
series section if you selected many
years you'll notice you can take the
horizontal bar on the bottom of the
table and scroll side to side and
compare figures for GDP and its major
components over the years
want to drop the data you pulled click
the drop button located next to the
modify button
after selecting the chart button you'll
automatically see your economic data in
the line chart format you can select a
maximum of 10 categories to chart at one
time
if you prefer a bar chart just click the
bar chart icon located between category
sections and the chart
also take notice of the gray and blue
line at the very bottom of the chart at
the end of the bar you'll see something
that looks like a pause button hover
over one of those two buttons and drag
them to the left or right this allows
you to zoom in and focus on specific
years of your choice the remaining
buttons are the download and print
button in the current chart format these
are all grayed out but don't worry
that's not a glitch the download and
print options are available on the graph
itself
if you want to download your chart just
click the arrow in the upper right
corner of the chart this gives you the
option to download or save the chart to
your computer to download share or print
information in the table format you need
to select the table button to get out of
the chart format
next click the download button we offer
three downloadable formats Microsoft
Excel Adobe PDF or CSV format you can
also map your data let's get started by
selecting GDP and personal income under
the regional data section then select
interactive data mapping
you can see the economic data by state
metro area or County
let's find the personal income of some
of the counties in Alabama
since we're searching for economic
information by County let's select
personal income and employment by County
here we can set the criteria for what we
want
let's leave the state selection on
Alabama and we'll leave other
preferences as it is select the year of
your choice then select Next Step
take your cursor and hover over any
County of your choice and you'll see
personal income features for that County
you can take that number and compare it
to the legend at the bottom of the map
hover over the down arrow or the
download button located in the upper
right section of the map and you'll see
the three download options for the map
you can also change from the map format
to either the chart or table format by
clicking on your preferred button do you
have questions
check out the FAQs methodologies and Bea
contact emails on our website or call
our customer service line at
301-278-9004
we'll help you find the data you need to
better understand the economy
that's what we do at Bea